the more signal you give to the
algorithm
uh the better the algorithm performs
right uh you know in
the pre-att world if you give more
purchases
the better the algorithm performs
obviously the algorithm would take
purchases from you and everybody else in
the world and it would just do better
now obviously it's just taking your
trials and doing much much better
hey you're listening to the sub club
podcast a show dedicated to the best
practices for building and growing
subscription app businesses we'll share
insider secrets from the top
subscription apps on the app stores
let's get into the show
welcome to the sub club podcast i'm your
host david bernard and with me as always
jacob biting hello jacob
hi david here with you as always
our guest today is shamanth brow founder
and ceo at rocketship hq host of the
podcast mobile user acquisition show and
lead instructor at the workshop series
mobile growth lab shimant's company
rocketship hq is a boutique growth
marketing agency with eight figures in
managed spend prior to founding
rocketship hq chamonte laid growth
marketing leading to three exits
hey shamath welcome to the podcast
honored to be here thank you for having
me david and jacob yeah so um i wanted
to start with a little bit of of a
history lesson you've been in in mobile
advertising and working on mobile apps
for
uh since very early
and so could you take just a couple of
minutes and step us through
the history of kind of what led us to
today with app tracking transparency
uh and all the different ups and downs
and and changes that have happened over
the past decade
yeah
there's been a lot of ups and downs
as you said but i think that i see two
overarching trends
but for folks who want to go into the
weeds
i would actually recommend two podcast
episodes one with mine with you david uh
it is called a brief history of app
store monetization
you provide a very great perspective
into
how the app store itself has changed
over the years
uh the other one was uh an interview i
did with david phillips i just titled a
brief history of device identifiers that
you know we're all about brief histories
over here
but
uh i think pertinent to what we're
talking about
att and how that
essentially disrupted growth marketing
today
there have been two forces that have led
us to this point
uh
which
over the last decade or so
right and i think it's important to know
and understand both of these
just to know how we got here
and why it's important right because
this att just did not happen overnight
edt prepared with signs for a decade and
uh you know
i think obviously a lot of this is
evident in retrospect
uh but i think it's people to know and
understand
what those breadcrumbs were trend number
one was that there has been increasing
accumulation of purchase data by
platforms over the last decade
you know i remember
you know david as you pointed out i am a
really old person who was around when
google advertising just took off uh with
all this grey hair
uh but you know when i started that we
were doing cpc buys ppm buys
i started doing mobile advertising
before facebook even had mobile ads
mobile app ads
right and
there was no conversion tracking uh
you know in fact i
yeah there was like no conversion
tracking if you you would buy installs
and you're like oh we bought so many
stuff we got so many purchases then
we we are profitable and we spent like
millions on games at the time and some
of the roles had it right so
it
certainly the level of sophistication
that emerged in mobile advertising
i don't think we could have posted in
2012 2013 2014
but one of like i said
from the tpc buys gradually they were
cpi buys
as ad networks that now are billion
dollar companies iron source and
applause and they were tiny ad networks
at the time a lot of others basically
fell by the wayside
uh you know they were like we have
enough confidence to be able to build
for install rather than just a click
upper impression just because we have
that kind of data that kind of
confidence the next step really was
facebook's aeo or purchase optimization
this is
2016 right which is
which seems so recent
and it's so staggering to think that we
could not optimize for purchases like
athletes today six six years ago
uh it's crazy
and that was just the biggest game
changer and i still remember
having a lot of skepticism
that this would even work and i'm like
how how are they going to find out who's
going to purchase they've never done it
nobody's done it but clearly somebody
could do it in this facebook right so
they had the purchase of data and i
think only
subsequent to that point of time
i think it became evident to me myself
that as to why facebook was so
successful because
they because basically of the idsa right
idfa and google id uh they had that idf
uh with print
from their family of assets certainly on
facebook audience networks so they were
able to predict
with easy accuracy
who the purchasers were obviously they
took it a step further with a
robot optimization right so
and obviously the more data facebook's
uh uh sdk got
the better it got at predicting who the
purchasers were obviously the uh the
more data the pixels on the web got
the bet the better the accuracy of the
sdk became and the other way around
right because they had you know if you
made a purchase on a beauty website you
would make a purchase on a on an
e-commerce app so they put all of that
data together right so obviously google
had a very very similar trajectory i
don't want to go too much into the reads
but
over the last decade increasing amount
of data got accumulated by facebook by
google
folks like app login and i and source
all the ad networks everybody got
increasing amount of data about user's
purchase of it obviously they just
weren't doing this in isolation apple
why isn't up to this
uh you know google well google had a
conflict because they were also making
money off of this they are also making
money off of this now so they have been
less active and pushing back but
you know
apple said uh-huh these you know you
know apples
again not to go too much into the weeds
but it's part corporate strategy
to but for apple to say aha we have
private reminders but it's also
very very much about profits for them uh
they are promoting their own ad network
now i'll be
i i don't know i don't have a lot of
confidence to how they will do anyway
right so apple said you know look we had
this udid which is non-resettable
let's space it out let's have an idfa
which is resettable which turned out
wasn't too much of an improvement then
they said oh
let's make this uh
idf is zero but
idf is zero which means if a user goes
on and turns off the lat that idsa
becomes zero and advertisers could not
cannot target people
shockingly enough prior to ids zero
which was i think 2016 they still had
lot
but if a user turned off light it just
meant advertisers please don't crack the
fuse it was almost like a request
it was a non-enforceable request
basically that these don't track me
but obviously nobody cares right
anyway so even lab zero was a very very
telltale sign that this is where
att is where apple is headed
and if you had to look on the web
uh safari had intelligent tracking
prevention they have obviously been much
more active on the web in terms of
privacy crackdowns uh mozilla had what
what's called etp i think it's called
efficient tracking prevention i forget
what it's called but then chrome of
course said hey we're going to deprecate
cell body cookies they've extended the
deadline but there's been a lot going on
in the direction of privacy
right uh and this that has happened very
very much in parallel with increasing
accumulation of data by platforms
and to some extent you know it hasn't
been surprising for anyone who's
followed the breadcrumbs that's gone to
zero and 2018 apple said
kids apps will not allow tracking that
was almost like a trial balloon for hg
and of course 20 20 80 hit
it was
not unsurprising i would say
that uh it came to be just because of
everything over the last decade that i
just described yeah that's a that's a
really great way to summarize it is
those two parallel courses with
it's like in the shadows there was like
more and more and more more data
accumulation feeding all of this but
simultaneously there was more and more
and more awareness of privacy concerns
and
what that data was being used for and
that you know it does seem like the
press you know had a big influence in
this i mean when because the new york
times and wall street journal both had
big posts in like 2017 2018
um where they showed you know how you
could track individual users and when
they're going to
you know a certain medical clinic or
yeah there was another set of stories
around u.s service members who were
being tracked by fitness apps and
revealing uh basic uh um
we call unknown previously unknown uh
military installations and things like
that so yeah
yeah there was
a lot going on that has led us to this
point so
so now apple has
has dropped the bomb
after acting transparency you you're
you're you're not allowed to track
unless you first prompt
and you know we could we could talk an
hour on all the different motivations
and the
um and even the way they deliver it you
know the way they request the prompt is
is and the wording of the prompt
has has even drawn controversy but let's
not get into that
i still every time it comes up i still
don't know what to click
but let's talk about the real world
impacts because i think there's been a
lot of ink spilled and a lot of
discussions around um
around those other things but but what i
want to hear from you as someone who
manages a ton of span and works in the
industry and
uh and has to deal with this day in day
out
um let's talk through the real real
world impacts of of of how this is
impacting the apps that you work with
and what you've seen kind of in the
broader industry i thought it was
interesting before we jumped on the on
the and started recording you actually
said uh you were expecting a crazier
summer so let's just start with that so
you're not quite seeing the disruption
you initially expected is that
oh am i overreading that i i don't want
to be grandstanding here but i certainly
was prepared for part far worse
uh right
and i don't want to jinx this but
certainly that couple of
advertisers we're working with that are
doing all right that are actually
growing but i'll talk about the
mechanics that may have contributed to
that further on
right uh
but i certainly was prepared for far far
far worse i would say yeah so so what
are you seeing i mean um
and then one of the things you you've
mentioned before is that you are seeing
some shift to android tell me about that
uh shift to android spend and is that in
certain categories across the board i i
think it's across the board i think it's
much more so in gaming
and if you look at a bunch of mmp
reports and estimates they peg
the
shift to about ios spend dropped to
about 30 to 40 percent
uh i think that sounds like a realistic
range obviously there's some verticals
that i hit much much harder uh right and
yeah um
but definitely i think there's a lot of
spence shifting to android
i would attribute some of that to the
fact that
tracking is broken but performance isn't
you know oh
uh to see this
uh right and it's like a number of folks
we work with and we also advise and i've
just talked to you they're like oh my
god my cpa is reported by facebook is
terrible because facebook start tracking
everything
and then when we look at their blended
numbers which is basically the money
they make and the trials they get and
the subscriptions they get or the
questions they get it's all right you
know it's
which is exactly what i mean by not
being as creepy bad as i expected you
know
if you look at the itunes dashboards
you're like you think all right you
you know you didn't
just go
crashing down which is what i was afraid
would happen
right right
that has not happened so no but what is
real and true is like i said tracking is
broken
even if performance is not right and
tracking's just broken just because
apples have
a concept of privacy threshold
which basically means
if a campaign
does not have a minimum number of
installs or purchases
apple is going to show zero in stock
zero purchases they report all installed
but they report very few purchases what
that means is if you are let's just say
a casual game or a social casino app
that has
a cost per purchaser of 150 to 200
which is not uncommon for these apps
then each campaign if you're running 500
a day per campaign you get two purchases
of three purchases per campaign
which just gets obfuscated by the
privacy threshold
which means
if you run a 500 already campaign you're
probably getting purchases you're just
not seeing them uh which is
better than a world where i'm not going
to purchase it
so
yeah
are we are we back to the old days of um
of
half your advertising budget is working
you just don't know which half yeah yeah
yeah yeah yeah it's very much true yeah
i was gonna ask so the pullback on the
spend like is that do you know where
that's coming from along the chain is
that is that companies not being sure
anymore and pulling back is it is it
agencies is it all long because at some
point somebody has to because i it makes
sense that like well one we don't know
how effective all this stuff was to
begin with right so just losing the
tracking
doesn't necessarily mean it's less
effective it just means we don't know
um and so it seems a little foolhardy to
just dial back right um
yeah you know especially if your
business relies on it but it seems like
that's what most at least some
percentage of companies have done
they've they've pulled back just because
they're not sure yeah i think i will
also say a lot of companies that have
pulled back have had relatively strong
android products
uh the couple of companies that i know
that are doing very well on ios now they
actually don't have very strong android
products and they were like
we don't have a choice right we don't
have a choice we'll do what it takes uh
i i obviously yeah i don't necessarily
need to apply that strong guys will be
rather short performance but
having a fallback means all right we're
going to take ios a little bit easy
we'll transfer into android
while we figure out what is going on did
you get to your question i think a lot
of that's coming from
companies uh especially larger
established companies that have had
bi teams and reporting systems and
dashboards that report on d7 pro at the
creative level
are like
we just don't have that in our report
anymore and they're spending too much to
be confident in just yolo
yeah yeah yeah yeah are you seeing any
specific trends on on cpms and cross
petrol or anything like that as far as
with the drop in
spend on ios and the increase on android
has some of the performance on ios not
degrading been more to do with market
dynamics changing versus it actually
just working as efficiently
yeah uh you know i i try not to look at
cpms just because cpms are very
contingent on
the kind of optimization you have like
you know in april if you had value
optimization you would be paying cpm
that went through the roof
and your cpms on audio network would be
higher than instagram and facebook and
the cpm is a little bit of a fuzzy
metric
what i like to look at is really the cpa
which is a cost per trial
which also has become fuzzy because of
the privacy threshold so now it's
blended cost per trial which right
steady now back to your question to your
underlying question about do i attribute
that to the underlying market dynamics
definitely i think that the fact that
there's less of competition i do think
has contributed to
uh
the seat blended cpa being steady for
folks that have continued to do ios
definitely i do think that uh the lesser
competition has played into that yeah
that makes sense let's talk a little bit
because this is kind of our wheelhouse
at uh rubycat obviously um nice shirt by
the way jacob
this is the original first ever revenue
cat t-shirt nice how how are
subscription apps being impacted
in in what you've seen and then how is
that different from
your games and other categories that
you're working with
yeah uh i would say subscription apps
are hit much much less hard than
a lot of games again
uh i just qualify i don't want to sound
like i'm grandstanding because this is
not like
a party or fiesta yet but i think
they're doing better than
folks who
are
really clueless i don't want to be
clueless but folks should just
are struggling you know i talked about
you know let's just say a hypothetical
casual game or a social casino app that
has a cost per page user of 150
they get killed by the privacy threshold
a subscription app is
less impacted by that
uh
just because uh you know again your cost
per
trial which is the primary metric
nearly every subscription app optimizes
for
is
generally under fifty dollars which
means for the same five hundred dollar
budget you're getting
uh you get uh you're getting ten
purchases so you're less
susceptible to that privacy threshold
right
and the other factor that makes
the whole 80d tank
a lot easier for subscription apps
is that
nearly every subscription app i know has
90 plus of their free trials happen
within the first 24 hours of install
what that means
with in the att paradigm is
a lot lot
nearly all of that signal gets captured
by
the att algorithm by by sql network
algorithm
uh because scad network works of a
system of timers right uh
immediately after install a timer start
and after 24 hours the timer resets
if your
and then another resettable timer starts
and if no event has happened in that
second timer
all of the events that have happened
first get sent back to the uh get sent
back to apple
no other events get sent further and i'm
probably
definitely grossly simplifying with some
of this uh and i have a youtube video
that goes into all of this into the v6
people can check that out
but my point being the fact that
all of the tru nearly all the crimes
happen within the first 24 hours
make it relatively easier for
subscription apps to have the signal be
captured by
sql network that's another
reason why subscription apps do quite
well uh and obviously you know the most
signal you give to the algorithm uh the
better the algorithm performs right uh
you know in
the pre-att world if you give more
purchases
the better the algorithm performs
obviously the algorithm would take
purchases from you and everybody else in
the world and it would just do better
now obviously it's just taking your
trials and doing much much better and
another trend we've seen is that
web-based flows
work a lot better for subscription apps
than for games
again there are challenges and execution
but certainly
one of the things they've seen that a
lot of the relatively most successful
apps are doing in the post http world is
adopt web-based lows uh right
yeah so i i would say those are some of
the factors that i can contribute to
subscription apps being better off than
games
in the post att work uh again not to
grandstand not to declare this a victory
yet but i think that they're much much
better off yeah there's there's still
also just the dynamic with consumable
games like i don't know what retention
curves really look like and stuff like
this but with subscriptions
you know your acquisitions you're making
today only affect you know a chunk of
your revenue in the very short term
versus and you have this like recurring
user base versus consumables if your new
users dry up really fast like
you're suddenly you've suddenly lost a
lot of uh yeah a lot of your business
model doesn't work as well right so yeah
um but wow that's incredible that the so
on those cpi's uh for like social
casinos or whatever which i imagine is
just a high spend category highly
competitive space so if they don't have
like value attribution
what's actually driving the cpi so high
like how do they know like what users to
spend that much money on is it just
is it just i guess click base like they
still like they can they can proxy and
know like people that click on those are
part of that high value group or or what
what what keeps the
what keeps the targeting good enough so
that you know because you can imagine if
everything was perfectly anonymous all
cpi's clicks would be the same right
across all apps yeah yeah yeah
at this point
i don't
i would not say we have a perfect answer
for
us with high cpa i think the best we
have right now is
treat
facebook reported metrics of platform
reported metrics as directional which
means
your cpa today would not be comparable
to your pre att cpa
but because it's going to be very very
high just because of the privacy
threshold that i just described that if
you're getting maybe 500
cp on this and 700 on that then you just
in for campaign is better than campaign
fees
but you're not inferring that your that
is your actual cost of acquisition so
you're taking the cpa as a relative
measure and i think that's true for the
casual game as it is for subscription
apps you're treating the cpa as a
relative measure between campaign and
campaign not so much as an
absolute measure of
unit economics i think that's a great
point to transition into
what's actually working right now so
we're talking about some of the impacts
but
um
i mean what you're kind of hinting at is
something that you've mentioned before
is that the the best source of truth now
is not
these
highly specific return on ad spend
calculation but actually using blended
metrics so tell me a little bit about
how how you approach
thinking about
blended metrics as a source of truth
versus you know the past you know five
or six years where it's way more focused
on
um
very detailed return on ad spend and
again to our earlier point even if that
return on ad spend calculation wasn't
actually as accurate as it seemed
you know you were at least able to
calculate it more accurately now it's
like kind of everything's out the window
so how are you approaching blended spend
or blended metrics uh to measure these
things
yeah i will add the caveat that the
blending metrics isn't
like modern or new
right it's
what old school
offline advertising worked with right
they were like oh this is how much i
spent this is how much i made that's how
they measured everything before the
internet
and even with the internet like
a
couple of companies we worked with
even pre-att worked with blended metrics
because they're like
look we know that a portion of our paid
installs drive organics we have a very
very clear correlation between updated
organic
so we've been we would be leaving money
on the table
if all we took into account with paid
users and not organics so you know
people we work with have definitely done
that and they're companies that have
done it just to pursue top-line growth
they're like look we need to grow as
aggressively as possible
and the way to do that is to
take blended metrics to justify the
growth rather than to shackle ourselves
by they take
uh just page robot
without your question how how
practically how do we sort of look at
this it just basically
means
we'll instead of saying
uh
this campaign gave us
uh a d7 return on ad spend of 20
or d7
cost per trial of 30
you're basically saying your overall
marketing spent gave you
a a 20
cost per trial
across paid and organic and social and
everything that you're spending on right
obviously that means
a lot of people tend to be uncomfortable
with that because they're like oh
you know if i hadn't spent on marketing
i would have still gotten 200 trials a
day
uh and i'm giving credit to marketing
for that and you know
i don't have a direct answer to that but
i think that our answer really is would
you want to be
would you want a model that's helpful in
helping you grow or would you want a
model that's accurate but is it helping
you grow and i'm not going to clean i
have an answer to that one
right but uh yeah so
you're basically looking at your total
number of trials
and your totals spent uh
and obviously this calculation becomes
heavier if you have multiple channels
if you're running google facebook map
and multiple ad networks then you're
like oh you know
my one of the ad networks probably
performed badly
but my total blend has not changed all
that much because my other channel was
like ten percent design stuff so there
are challenges especially at large
levels to spend
but
it is a very solid source of truth
especially for smaller advertisers who
may be on a handful of channels because
it comes out of your ideas it's what you
see in the bank and um you also
mentioned that um
sending people
you mentioned webflows are working
really well and i assume what you meant
by that is sending people from an ad
into
onto the web instead of onto the app
store which is it's really fascinating
to me on multiple levels because
you know
the app stores have always been this
black box where you you put a certain
number of of clicks into it and then you
know you see the end result but you
don't see any of the steps in between i
mean you have some basic metrics with
app store
analytics and stuff
but with the web i would imagine that
that gives you a more direct
trackable
um
link from somebody who
sees an ad to then actually kind of
what they're doing on your website so
but then ultimately i've talked to a lot
of developers who talk about how on the
web their conversions are actually quite
a bit lower than in the app because
apple's made it so easy to use in-app
purchase
so but it seems like maybe there is
somewhat of a balance there is that
maybe you lose fewer people
from having to jump through those hoops
of installing the app before they even
get to the onboarding before they can be
shown
um you know the value proposition and
then being you know shown a subscription
page or whatever it is what
have you seen working in regard to web
flows and then and specifically for for
subscription apps yeah yeah yeah like i
said uh i've certainly seen a lot of
success for subscription apps that have
adopted web flows
uh and a couple of apps i've worked with
they've seen month-on-month growth
through atg
again nothing has a typical uh result
but it definitely
does happen but i think a couple of
elements you know uh i think it's what's
most important is to make sure that low
is right and there's a couple of
possible flows uh uh i think it's
important to think to which one is right
really let's figure out what's right
right i think one flow could be
shown that
a user goes to a landing page which is
basically like a b2b or a b2c landing
page on the web or what you would get
for a web product
and you have a link that
accept the call to call to action on the
landing pages go to the app store
so
a lot of the experience purchase and
trial experience happens on the app
store
the web page
i
actually does the job of selling the
user on the product
and it's my hypothesis that this
actually works well because
the webpage can do a much much better
job of selling than the app store can
uh while we're still making it clear
that this is an app
uh and while the actual conversion
happens within the app itself
but uh somewhat similar uh
a different flow that's
very comparable would be
take a laser to an ad
take a user from an ad to a landing page
where users have to input their phone
number which again get a user to
make it makes it clear to the user that
this is an app this is a mobile
experience a user gets a text message
and user signs up for it uh yeah and and
when they click on the text message they
get to go to the app store and download
the app
right uh
again another model could be a user
clicks on an ad goes to an article or a
content page
which is
what you would see if you had a taboola
or not brain ad again article or a
content page
leads to an app store
and i think
the last and i think the more complex
sort of
flow is just to have on board them on
the web uh basically take them to a web
page and they
on board on the web
and uh
to hopefully also actually make the
purchase on the web in which case you
save the 30
this is to be honest the hardest and the
most resource-intensive and really it's
my recommendation that you pursue that
path
after you pursue one of the other
paths that i recommended because
you don't want to invest a ton of
engineering and development time in
building a web onboarding flow
if you don't even know that the web flow
is going to work for you uh so i would
recommend just testing the web landing
pages first and then using the web
onboarding so
but uh yeah i think those are some of
the
most important models that we see work
something else i think that's also very
very critical is i think a lot of people
when
they look at
a lot of advertisers i know that have
started on the web for the first time
were like oh let's
put together this nice landing page that
looks like our home page
uh on our website and just put it out
there
that doesn't work
very well unless you're being very
intentional about
what value propositions to touch on the
actual layout of your landing page and
we have a structure that we use now
which is like
your most important uh page point and
value proposition goes to the header
then there's social proof then your most
important emotional benefits then the
teachers i think the most successful
advertisers we work with
are very very intentional about
what that web page is looking like and
they also test rigorously uh i think
that all of those elements are very very
critical to making the web flow work
yeah that's really smart and i hadn't
thought of it quite that way about how
you know and as i was talking with the
app store being the black box is you
you're just sending somebody hoping they
look at the screenshots hoping the icon
resonates with them hoping the title and
subtitle are meaningful
but when you send them to the web it's
not just about you know pushing them
right to subscribe on the web but it's
actually just
having a better opportunity to
communicate the value prop so that by
the time they get to the app store they
are
they have a much higher uh
incentive they have a higher um they're
just more likely to actually take action
by the time they do get to the app store
so that makes a lot of sense tells you a
lot about the uh quality of like the app
store as a sales pitch right
yeah i guess when you're like looking at
a you know you're trying to
differentiate right and and there's only
so much you can communicate in a block
of text and then a bunch of screenshots
right you've seen so much data shoved
into the screenshots on amazon
right they're not screen shots right
they're like a slide deck yeah little
billboards yeah yeah yeah yeah i also
think another reason why
the app store works so worked so well
pre-att was facebook would just show ads
to
users to install other subscription apps
so if you send them directly to the
astro they're almost pre-qualified
which is great anymore
so i think the webs level the field
uh a lot
yeah it's it's it's a tough um skill set
though for a lot of developers because
like they don't often have web
experience internally and i think i
think i hear so much like people get so
obsessed about the 30
um and they want to jump straight to
that last one you mentioned about
building a whole online purchasing thing
which like you know stripes pretty easy
to use like it's it's you know it's not
that much more work than building a
landing page but you have to remember
um okay management so now you gotta have
a link where somebody can go and cancel
that thing now you also have to worry
about taxes stripe doesn't like to
collect uh tax information for you
already you have to you know then
synchronize that with your back end and
you know if you're using revenue casinos
with us or whatever but you got to
manage all that too it adds a lot of
complexity um for 30 right and when
you're just trying to you know all of
these things can find incremental growth
yeah but like as you're saying it's
important to
put them in the right order or you can
end up wasting a lot of energy and money
yeah yeah yeah well i did want to to
move on to the um
the future so we
we've kind of
gotten through the first couple of
months of this uh this rough patch and
are into this um
new era of of mobile advertising are
there any things that you're seeing
that are especially promising
that you think
are the future like is the future
everything we've been discussing so far
of just 50 of your advertising works and
50 doesn't and you're never going to
know which or do you or are there some
technologies coming online or some
approaches that that are just going to
take time to kind of work out
yeah i think there's going to be some
changes i don't know if these are going
to be
earth shattering uh in terms of changing
what's necessary normal with atp
i think the most promising though i
would say uh ios 15
custom product pages uh
basically
you know it solves the problem with gk
viewer and during the just
you have one small slide deck and
everybody sees the same thing and astro
does a
terrible job of telling a user on
what the product is basically with the
custom product features you can have up
to 35 versions of your app store
uh which means you're like if you're a
you know wellness app
uh
if let's just say you're like a
meditation app that has uh meditations
for sleep or anxiety and how to meditate
you can have
a separate landing page so to speak on
the app store for sleep anxiety
meditation right uh and you can send
you get a unique url for each of these
so
presumably you can have an ad for sleep
going to an app store for each sleep as
for anxiety going to an app store for
anxiety
i think that can help i just don't think
it's going to have too much on the
measurement front
obviously the
actual execution is still unclear the
announcements out so i think definitely
one of the bigger
changes i would say that's coming with
rs15
the other other one would just be that
uh advertisers are going to be receiving
postbacks which is huge uh at least an
ensuring accuracy of the advertising
data so far what's completely bonkers
right now is
networks like facebook snap everybody
gets
your post back from s-cad network but
you as advertiser you as an advertiser
do not
which means you basically take the word
for it uh i do know
for a fact that tick tock has actually
changed values i don't want to call it
malicious because the conversion value
was null and they changed it to zero
uh
the problem is that null and zero have
very very different meaning zero means
install and null means an install happen
and there's just no value so i know that
they did that change i don't have their
continuity to do it so
uh
but my point is
and google
explicitly says we are going to use
model conversions which basically
take our word for it
facebook says campaign data is accurate
everything underneath is modeled which
means take our word for it
with which all of this is because
the post pack goes to
the networks but not the advertiser
with ios 15 if the post back goes to the
advertiser you can at the very least
verify
they're telling the truth with
bonkers considering i think david you
imagine
uh until all this time
you you just have to take the platform's
word for it even pre-att
uh right
uh i think that's going to be
that's going to be a big big change even
though a lot of that's going to happen
under the hood and i say advertisers for
the vast majority of advertisers the mmp
is going to do the receiving
uh of the uh postpartum but i think
that's going to be a big deal
but i think those are some of the big
changes the custom product pages and the
postdoctoral advertisers but really in
terms of the future
in many ways i do think it's going to be
back to 2013 or 2014.
i think i talked about how we bought a
number of installs and we hope that in a
certain percentage well we knew that
certain percentage of them would convert
to purchases that would be for
subscription so there weren't really
trials but i think it's going to be a
very similar world we're going to be
you're going to have to be more
comfortable
making decisions based off of incomplete
data
but i do see that in the future one of
the things i've been hearing a lot about
since since apple announced att last
year is incrementality testing so
systematically turning on and off you
know so if you're advertising i mean
obviously this would be a tool for for
larger apps but if you're advertising
across facebook google snap tick tock
and you know other mobile dsps
you know systematically moving spend
around and then
measuring the difference or even turning
spend off in certain channels and
increasing spend in other channels
um
have you seen
that work um and are you um excited
about the potential
of having tools in this space or or do
you think incrementality testing is a
bit over hyped so i think
with any recommendation like
incrementality i think the one caveat
that a lot of people miss is
that it's useful for a very very tiny
fraction of advertisers david like you
said if you are on
like
all cell solubility networks multiple
dsps multiple ad networks influencers tv
yes absolutely you know you should use
incrementality because there's just no
way you're going to find out if this is
going to work an incrementality and
medium x modeling you want to use both
of them and to make that work but i
would say the kinds of advertisers who
need something like this are a very tiny
fraction
so the vast majority of advertisers even
the advertisers who are on four to five
channels
even advertisers will spend low six
figures in
uh monthly spend
i don't think uh incrementality or
testing is going to be very
helpful or actionable just because
it's hard uh you know it's
it just becomes imprecise at small
volumes of data you need
a critical mass of data for your
analysis to be useful
uh right
and i think it's a very similar thing
with vdmx models right you need enormous
enormous budgets
for those to be useful and helpful so i
i do think
these are great but
i think the fact that they're not an
antidote to all of the havoc that att
has uh brought us about
they're applicable to a tiny flavor of
the advertisers out there yeah that
makes sense and then
if if you're only advertising on google
or only advertising on facebook or only
advertising on the two of them i mean
they're they're essentially doing some
level of incrementality testing for you
right they're they're measuring the
performance of this campaign against
that campaign and they're
ramping up
depending on the results they they seem
to be seeing so that some of that's kind
of already covered if you're using those
platforms
uh as your primary sources um
another thing i i wanted to get your
thoughts on was experimentation with
other forms of advertising you're you're
very focused you know currently on on
um you know paid user acquisition and i
don't think that's going away and i
think for you know for a lot of apps
that is going to be the the the best
most reliable way to continue scaling
even without accurate measurement but
have you seen any other
uh pushes with any of your customers um
to work on on
on different styles of advertising
different uh approaches to marketing
that are being successful and do you see
they're kind of more incentive to try
more things these days you know i spoke
about web and i think there's definitely
much much stronger interest in web
campaigns than even six months ago
uh
at larger budgets there's definitely
stronger interest in
influencers
but i would again uh much like with the
incrementality i would say if you're on
smaller budget i do not recommend
experimenting i do not recommend
diversifying certainly at larger budgets
and i would also say folks that are that
were spending
in the tens of millions in budget
folks like that would have been
or even like millions a month uh they
certainly found the larger studios they
have already been on influencers they've
already been advertising on tv but none
of this would be new to them yeah so i
don't know if there's anything radically
new that we see yeah and then that kind
of gets back to the the good old tried
and true just
got to build a good product and work on
your monetization and kind of get back
to the basics of product as well i think
sometimes these these overly complex
overly
targeted
systems especially for people who make
software can tend to be busy boxes right
they can tend to be
they can tend to be things that like con
attract our attention and and because
they they seem very like you know oh we
can get it right and really make it
scale and some people have right it's
possible but
80 20 i think for a lot of people out
there like just just just focus on the
fundamentals and you can go pretty far
and then as time comes you can layer in
the more you know yeah yeah complexity
and precision yeah yeah and like i said
at a certain level of scale
tv influences all of this becomes much
much more meaningful
uh
and like i said that's certainly more
meaningful already but yeah you don't
need too much that's fancy well i think
that's a great place to wrap up uh it
was great chatting with you and and uh a
lot of insight there on what's working
and and what how to think about things
in this this new world of mobile
marketing
um you know as we wrap up is there any
uh last thoughts uh we're gonna include
links to uh
uh where people can find you on on on
the web and to rocket ship hq and
whatnot uh anything else you wanna share
oh no as well like i said i think
this
this was not as bad as it as we thought
it would be
uh certainly there's ways to
mitigate
the worst case scenarios
uh some of which hopefully i've been
able to share uh
so uh hopefully
they'll come out on the other side of
all of this without
too much craziness i think people are
gonna keep using apps that's my that's
my prediction
and i think people are going to keep
advertising apps yeah yeah yeah yeah
it's the how that's going to have to
change and it has to change dramatically
and there's no
getting around that well it was great
chatting with you and uh we'll talk
again soon absolutely later yeah thank
you bye
to make sure you never miss an episode
subscribe to the show and your favorite
podcast player thanks so much for
listening until next time
[Music]